<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Shannon &amp; Dijkstra</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="shannon_title">Claude Shannon</string>
    <string name="shannon_info">Claude Shannon was an American mathematician, electrical engineer, and cryptographer known as "the father of information theory".
                                Born in 1916, Shannon graduated from the University of Michigan in 1936 with two bachelor\'s degrees in electrical engineering 
                                and mathematics. He then began his graduate studies in electrical engineering at MIT, where his master\'s degree thesis won him 
                                the Alfred Noble American Institute of American Engineers Award in 1939. Howard Gardner also praised his thesis, saying that it 
                                was \"possibly the most important, and also the most famous, master\'s thesis of the century". \n \n
                                
                                During WWII Shannon undertook important studies into what would become the field of Information Theory, fire-control systems, 
                                and cryptography (where he worked with Alan Turing for some months in Washington). A notable achievement of his was proving that 
                                the cryptographic one-time pad is unbreakable, and that any unbreakable system must have certain characteristics (such as a truly 
                                random key, etc). \n \n
                                
                                He also founded the field of Information Theory, where he made massive contributions to natural language processing and digital 
                                signal transmission. \n \n 
                                
                                His interests were not limited to his work however. Among other things he invented the \'Theseus\' (as seen in the above image), 
                                an electromechanical mouse that could navigate different mazes and learn from it\'s experience. It is considered to be the first 
                                artificial learning device of it\'s kind. \n \n
                                
                                He developed Alzheimer\'s disease as he got older, and spent his last years in a nursing home Massachusetts. He died in 2001, 
                                leaving behind a rich legacy.\nNeil Sloane has stated that \"He\'s one of the great men of the century. Without him, none of the 
                                things we know today would exist. The whole digital revolution started with him\".</string>
                                
    <string name="dijkstra_title">Edsger Dijkstra</string>
    <string name="dijkstra_info">Edsger Dijkstra was a Dutch computer scientist. He was born in Rotterdam in 1930, and originally studied theoretical physics at Leiden 
                                 University but soon switched to computer science. He held positions at the Mathematisch Centrum, Eindhoven University of Technology, 
                                 Burroughs Corporation, and the University of Texas at Austin. \n \n
                                 
                                 Among his contributions to computer science are a shortest path algorithm (also know as Dijkstra\'s algorithm), the Shunting yard 
                                 algorithm, the THE multiprogramming system, the Banker\'s algorithm, and the semaphore construct for coordinating multiple processors 
                                 and programs. Another concept due to Dijkstra in the field of distributed computing is that of self-stabilization – an alternative 
                                 way to ensure the reliability of the system. Dijkstra\'s algorithm is used in SPF, Shortest Path First, which is used in the routing 
                                 protocols OSPF and IS-IS. \n \n
                                 
                                 On a more humorous note, Dijkstra was also responsible for the introduction of the term \'Considered Harmful\' into the field of 
                                 computer science. He started it by writing a paper critizizing excessive use of the GOTO statement, and it was published by the 
                                 ACM as "Go To Statement Considered Harmful"; a response to this paper was entitled "\'Go To Statement Considered Harmful\' Considered 
                                 Harmful", and the response to that paper was entitled ""\'Go To Statement Considered Harmful\' Considered Harmful" Considered Harmful?"
                                 
                                 He died in Nuenen on 6 August 2002 after a long struggle with cancer. The following year, the ACM PODC Influential Paper Award in 
                                 distributed computing was renamed the Dijkstra Prize in his honor.</string>

</resources>
